National Child Labor Committee Publications 5242
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
National Child Labor Committee Publications
1904-1971
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
National Child Labor Committee
5242
2 cubic feet
2 linear ft.
Records (documents), publications (documents).
Documents the remarkable campaign of the CIO to organize the South particularly in the textile, wood, chemical, oil, and iron and steel industries. In its emphasis on the need to organize Black and White workers in this part of the United States, certainly for the times, Operation Dixie was a "radical" movement.
5557172
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, July 29, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 22, 2017
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Child labor -- United States -- History; Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives; National Child Labor Committee (U.S.)
5557172
- Always, Lazelle D. "Will You Make A School?", 1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Jean Broadhurst (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Child Labor Amedment - Argument for Ratification, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Dinwiddle, Courtenay "How Good is the Good Earth?", 1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Folks, Gertrude "Farm Labor vs. School Attendance", 1920 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Congressman Israel M. Foster, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Raymond G. Fuller, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Gibbons, Charles E. "Child Labor in the Tiff Mines, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Gibbons, Charles E. et al. "Administration of the Child Labor Law in Ohio.", 1931 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Gibbons, Charles E. et al. When Children are Injured in Industry, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Gibbons, Charles E. et al. "School or Work in Indiana?", 1927 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Hudson, Manley O. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Lewis, William Draper and Waite, Edward F. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Lovejoy, Owen R. "Child Labor and Philantrophy", 1958 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- National Child Labor Committee. "The American Child" 1919-1963 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- National Child Labor Committee "Analysis of State Child Labor Laws (Box 1, Folder 16)
- National Child Labor Comm. "Annual Report - 53nd,-53rd", 1909-1959 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- National Child Labor Committee "The Changing years, 1904-1954 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- National Child Labor Committee. "The Child Labor Amendment", 1934 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- National Child Labor Committee "The Child Labor Amendment", 1935 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- National Child Labor Committee "Child Labor Facts - 1928" (Box 1, Folder 21)
- National Child Labor Committee. "Child Labor Facts, 1930" (Box 1, Folder 22)
- National Child Labor Committee "Child Labor Facts, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- National Child Labor Committee - "Child Labor Facts, 1932, 1933, 1935", 1932-1935 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- National Child Labor Committee. "Child Labor - Facts For Sermon or Lecture use", 1913 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- National Child Labor Committee "Child Labor vs. Work Experience", 1955 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- National Child Labor Committee "Child Laborers Today", 1938 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- National Child Labor Committee. "Child Welfare in North Carolina", 1918 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- National Child Labor Committee. "The Clinker ans Some Other Children", 1904 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- National Child Labor Committee. "Poems of Child Labor", 1924 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- National Child Labor Committee. "The Farmer - and the Federal Child Labor Amendment", 1934 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- National Child Labor Committee "The Federal Child Labor Amendment", 1940 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- National Child Labor Committee "Handbook on the Federal Child Labor Amendment", 1937 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- National Child Labor Committee "Minimum Standards" (Box 1, Folder 34)
- National Child Labor Committee. "Child Labor Facts" (Box 1, Folder 35)
- National Child Labor Committee - "More than Half a Million Left!", 1939 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- National Child Labor Committee. "News", 1935 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- National Child Labor Comm "A Pioneer Agency", 1904 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- National Child Labor Committee "The Doctor Looks at Child Labor", 1929 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- National Child Labor Committee "Publications List + Order Form", 1958 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- National Child Labor Committee "State Child Labor1947" (Box 1, Folder 41)
- National Child Labor Committee. "State Child Labor", 1950 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- National Child Labor Committee. "A Summer In the Country, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- National Child Labor Committee. "Where Shall They Go?" (Box 1, Folder 44)
- National Child Labor Committee "Where Work Begins", 1932 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- National Child Labor Comm "The Why and How of amending the Federal Child Labor Law", 1949 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- National Child Labor Comm. "Why the Newspapers Oppose the Federal Child Labor Amendment, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- National Child Labor Committee. "Will Your Arm Help?" (Box 1, Folder 48)
- National Child Labor Committee. "The Work of the National Child Labor Committee, 1904 to 1929, 1904-1929 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- National Child Labor Comm. "Youth and Work", 1955-1961 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- National Child Labor Committee "The Child Labor Bulletin", 1916 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- National Child Labor Committee. National Committee on Employment of Youth "HelpFor America's Children", 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- National Child Labor Committee on Employment of Youth. "Just a Minutes", 1960-1964 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- National Child Labor Committee. National Committee on Employment of Youth "The Next Step", 1964 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- National Child Labor Committee. National Committee on Employment of Youth. "Opportunity", 1963 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- National Child Labor Committee. National Committee on Employment of Youth "Progress", 1959-1962 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- National Child Labor Committee. National Committee on the Education of Migrant Children. "Publications", 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Lovejoy. Owen R. "Brief for the Federal children's Bureau", 1958 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Lovejoy, Owen R. six years Battles, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- National Child Labor Committee, "The Appeal of the Children.", 1914 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Ryan, John A. "The Proposed Child Labor Amendment" (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Sidel, Jones E., 1939 (Box 1, Folder 62)
- Swift, Wiley H. (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Florence, Taylor, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Zimand, Gertrude Folks, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Folks, Homer, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 66)
- Lovejoy, Owen R. "The Child in Industry", 1909 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- National Child Labor Committee "An' the Ball game starts in 15 minutes" (Box 1, Folder 68)
- National Child Labor Committee. "Announcing A Study Course On", 1935 (Box 1, Folder 69)
- National Child Labor Committee - "Child Labor Facts - 1938 (Box 1, Folder 70)
- National Child Labor Committee. "Child Labor Programs and Projects", 1930-1931 (Box 1, Folder 71)
- National Child Labor Committee "For the Child", 1932 (Box 1, Folder 72)
- National Child Labor Committee "It's Up to the States!" (Box 1, Folder 73)
- National Child Labor Committee. "The National Child Labor Committee" (Box 1, Folder 74)
- National Child Labor Committee " Ratify the Child Labor Amendment", 1934 (Box 1, Folder 75)
- National Child Labor Committee "Some Striking Facts For Consideration" (Box 1, Folder 76)
- National Child Labor Committee. Dept. of Research + Publicity "Congress and Child Labor", 1937 (Box 1, Folder 77)
- National Child Labor Committee. "It's Not Join" (Box 1, Folder 78)
- Non-Partisan Committee For Ratification of the Federal Child Labor Amendment, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 79)
- Wefer, Marion, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 80)
- Pound, Roscoe, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 81)
- Zimand, Gertrude Folks, ed., 1929 (Box 1, Folder 82)
- Zimand, Gertrude Folks "Child Labor Facts" - 1939 (Box 1, Folder 83)
- Miscellaneous Related Pamphlets, 1958-1964 (Box 1, Folder 84)
- HD 6250 U58 N272 No. 327-394 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- National Child Labor Board 1905-1908 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- HD 6250 U58 N@72 No. 153, 1912-1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- The Federal Children's Bureau, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- HD 5250 U58 N272 No. 24, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- HD 6250 U58 N272 No. 40, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- HD 6250 U58 N272 No. 37, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- HD 6250 U58 N272 No. 69, 1909-1911 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- HD 6250 U58 N272 No. 1, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- HD 6250 U58 N272, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- HD 6250 U58 N272, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 11)